welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to episode
135 of the listening Time Podcast I hope
you all had a good end of the year and I
hope that you're ready for
2024 and that you're motivated to make
this a good year for you and at the time
of recording this
it's still November I'm recording this
very early however uh when this is
released it will be
2024 so I want to make sure to wish you
all a Happy New Year and in today's
episode I want to talk about the fact
that it's going to be a new year uh when
this episode is released uh like I said
it's it's not a new year for me yet it's
still November but when this is released
it will be a new year and I want to have
a new mindset so this episode will be
mostly for myself I want to talk about
some of the things that I want to change
about my mindset uh but I think that you
might also benefit from it because maybe
these are also changes that you can make
to benefit your mindset this year so I
think that this will be a good topic uh
even though I'm talking to myself here I
am also going to relate it to uh people
in general so hopefully uh you'll
benefit from this and before we continue
remember that if if you want to really
improve your listening this year and you
want to uh start to understand native
speakers when they speak fast then make
sure to join my membership so you can
get my specialized listening training so
make sure to go down below and click on
the link in the episode description
that's
patreon.com time and if you feel ready
to practice your listening with real
convers ation uh then make sure to join
my us conversations podcast so that you
can practice with those real
conversations that I have with other
native speakers the link is also down
below that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you like this
podcast please share it with anyone else
you know who's learning English and
please give it a festar rating and write
a review all right let's get started are
your ears ready you know what time it is
it's listening
time okay let's talk about the new
mindset that I want to have this year
and that maybe some of you want to have
this year so the first thing that I want
to improve uh regarding my mindset this
year is that I want to view every day as
a gift I already do this and I
already understand this I get that this
is true that every day is a gift for me
however I don't act like it all the time
there are many times when I don't act as
if uh the fact that I'm alive today is a
gift and I kind of take it for granted
in English when we say that you take
something for granted what we're saying
is that you don't appreciate it you just
view it as obvious that it's true and
that you don't really stop to consider
that you just say oh yeah of course
you just take it for granted you don't
appreciate uh the significance of it so
uh for me I know that every day is a
gift but sometimes I take this for
granted and I don't really act like this
in my daily life I don't act the way I
want to act uh according to this idea so
when I say that every day is a gift what
I'm saying is that I need to understand
that I don't necessarily deserve good
things sometimes we can feel like that
that we deserve to have uh good things
if we have good things it's because
that's how it's supposed to be we
deserve that uh however I think that if
we have that type of thinking all the
time then we don't actually
appreciate the things that we have we
don't appreciate the good things in our
life because we view it as something
that we already deserve so why do we
need to appreciate it however I don't
want to have that Minds set I want to
have a
mindset uh where I consider every day to
be a gift that I don't deserve but God
gave it to me so I'm thankful I'm happy
and I'm going to appreciate this day and
I'm not only talking about the day but
all the things uh inside my my day all
the things that happen and that I have
and the experiences that I have uh I
need to view them as uh not things that
I just deserve but gifts that have been
given to me I think that's a good
attitude to have and in general uh with
this mindset I want to have more
gratitude uh gratitude refers to being
thankful for what you have so if I view
every day as a gift and I don't think
that I just deserve all of these good
things then I can be more grateful I can
be more thankful for the good things in
my life because uh for example when you
re receive a gift from someone else
you're thankful right you didn't have
that gift before no one um made that
person give you that gift because you
deserve it no the person just gave it to
you and you can appreciate it and be
grateful and so that's how I want to
view things that uh every good thing
that happens to me every good thing that
I have is not something that I deserve
it's a gift given to me and I can
appreciate it much more and just be
thankful throughout my day I think I've
talked about that in several episodes
but I think it's really important if
you're
grateful uh your life is going to be a
lot better because you actually
appreciate things so that's a big thing
and uh if I'm grateful for every day I
think that I'll
enjoy my day more I'll enjoy the little
things um the details that might seem
insignificant I can actually appreciate
these details more because I view them
as a gift and I don't just take them for
granted right so that's uh an effect of
viewing each day as a gift I think that
I'll be able to enjoy the little things
more and I want to do this because time
flies when I say that time flies I'm
saying that time goes by very fast I
want to stop and appreciate the good
things that I have because time goes by
fast and before you know it uh you're a
lot older and you haven't even
appreciated all of the cool amazing
things that you've had up until that
point so that's the first thing that I
want to improve about my mindset this
year I want to get better at viewing
things as
gifts that I receive and not thinking
that I just deserve those things right
so the next thing I want to improve
about my mindset is I want to have my
thoughts more balanced when it comes to
thinking about the past present and
future I think this is one that uh a lot
of people can and benefit from I'm sure
that a lot of you spend more time than
you'd like thinking about the past or
thinking about the future or living too
much in the present and not thinking
about the future for example so I think
that most of us can improve in this
regard and specifically
I need to improve uh by not thinking too
much about the future I'm the type of
person that thinks about the future all
the time I think about the future
constantly uh and I think that it's good
to think about the future there are some
great benefits to thinking about the
future of course however when you think
about the future too much then you run
into some problems in English when we
say that you run into something in this
context we mean that you encounter that
thing you encounter those problems so
more specifically uh because I think so
much about the future the future is
always on my mind because of this I deal
with
anxiety and I can't always enjoy the
present and this is something that I
really want to change um just like I
mentioned when talking about uh enjoying
the little things uh I want to be able
to enjoy the moment and not uh be
thinking about the future
when something uh really great or
precious is happening right now so I
want to balance that I'm not saying that
I don't want to think about the future
obviously not however I want to have
more time thinking about the present
let's say and if you're someone who
thinks about uh the past a lot lot for
example and I sometimes do this um you
might also have another issue of maybe
feeling uh like you're always regretting
things in the past and you can't enjoy
the present because of your past
mistakes or things like that and I think
it's good to recognize your mistakes uh
from the past for sure
however if you're constantly replaying
those in your mind and you're always
thinking about the past and things that
happened that can be another issue right
or maybe you don't just think about your
regrets from the past but maybe you
think a lot about how great the past was
and how uh things aren't good now but
they were great in the past that can be
a depressing thought right to think that
everything was better before and now
things aren't as good that's another
issue all right and I think that's a
common tendency that a lot of people
have uh we tend to view the past uh and
maybe exaggerate R how good it was but
really uh it wasn't that great and we're
just looking at it from uh a future
perspective and so the same thing will
probably happen 10 years from now you'll
look back to things that are current now
and you might think that the things uh
now uh are much better than the things
that uh will be happening in the future
for example so it's easy to fall into
that trap so I think it's important not
to spend too much time thinking about
the future or the past and it's also not
good to just always think about the
present and not think about the past or
the future because if you never think
about the past then you're never gonna
learn from your mistakes you're never
going to learn lessons from experiences
that you had um you might not appreciate
your memories from the past so that's
not good and if you don't think about
the future ever then you're not going to
have goals for yourself
you're not going to actually uh plan to
achieve certain things and uh you might
fall into the Trap of just wanting
pleasure now and that's not a good thing
either right we need to learn to also
delay our
gratification sometimes when you delay
your gratification we're saying that you
do the hard thing now or you don't uh
get the pleasure that you want now so
that you can have it in the future and
in a better form usually and that's an
important skill to have so uh that's why
it's also important to not just focus on
this moment and having fun right now and
that's it uh we also want to be able to
consider the future and the consequences
of our actions and have goals for
ourselves and um be able to Envision
ourselves in the future so I think
that's really important as well for me
in particular my problem is that I need
to not think too much about the future
and instead enjoy the moment more and uh
be present in the moment and enjoy the
little things uh that are happening
right now and appreciate what's
happening now so that's another thing
that I want to change another
Improvement that I need to make is that
I need to view uh things that happen to
me as not just happening to me but
happening for
me so I heard someone say this recently
and at first I thought it sounded kind
of cheesy uh when we say that something
is cheesy that means that it sounds kind
of cheap or unoriginal or inauthentic it
doesn't sound very good um I thought it
sounded kind of
cheesy but the more I think about it the
more true it is uh it seems pretty true
to me now that I consider uh this
sentence so things happen for me and not
to me what I'm saying is that uh we
often feel like we're just the victims
of everything that happens oh man this
happened to me he said that to me uh
that occurred and I just suffered the
consequences of all of this of course
that's the tendency of how we think
about um bad things or uh inconvenient
things or challenging things that's kind
of a normal tendency for people however
if we start to think about these things
as happening for us meaning they happen
for our
benefit then we can actually uh get
something good out of these situations
so if we view things as happening to us
that means that we complain and get mad
and uh are really negative about things
that we don't like that happened however
if we can uh view every challenge or
inconvenience or problem as an
opportunity to learn or grow or gain
experience from then uh things aren't so
negative we can try to take the positive
from every situation this is something
that I definitely need to work on I want
to start to view things as learning
experiences rather than just problems
that happened to me I really want to
improve in that regard and I want to
become stronger from the things that
happen to me that aren't so great I want
to use those things to become stronger
to become a better person uh to become
wiser by the way the word wise means
that you have a lot of intelligence
because of experience you're wise so I
want to become wiser and just learn from
these things instead of complaining
about them and feeling sorry for myself
I want to get better at seeing these
things from a different angle uh a more
positive angle so uh always asking
myself how can I learn from this
situation what can I gain from this
experience how can I become a better
person from this or what uh trait do I
need to develop or what skill do I need
to develop to better handle this
challenge right always trying to look
for uh how I can improve from the
situation so that's something I want to
get better at and I'm sure some of you
might also agree with me there that that
would be a better mindset to have and
lastly I want to give one bonus uh
mindset change here uh related to
language and language learning uh this
is a general one not just for me but I
wanted to give you this uh extra little
um encouragement here um so with
language learning we can sometimes have
a mindset where we want to rush things
we want it to go faster we're annoyed
when we feel that we're not making
progress and we get discouraged because
it doesn't seem like we're improving
fast enough so I think that it's better
to have the
mindset um where you are not rushing
don't rush there's no hurry here you're
always going to feel like you're failing
if if you have a mentality where you
want things done really fast you want
the Improvement uh to happen really
quickly that just simply doesn't happen
very often with language learning so if
you're listening to me right now that
means that you're practicing your
English and if you're practicing your
English you're improving even if you
don't feel like it even if you you don't
feel like the progress is happening if
you're actually practicing your English
you're doing you're listening maybe
you're speaking or whatever if you're
doing this practice you're
improving it might be happening very
slowly and you might not realize it but
if you're putting in the effort you're
improving because the words that you
hear me say and the phrases you hear me
use all of these things are um going
into your brain they might not stay
there but you're at least being exposed
to them and you're getting more of this
exposure to English uh every time you do
your listening practice and this is
helping your brain it's helping the
language learning process so this
process might be really slow but it's
happening and I think that uh the
mindset change that a lot of us need to
have me too I'm also guilty of this is
we need to not rush don't feel like the
progress needs to be fast because it
almost never feels like it's fast
especially once you reach an
intermediate level the progress usually
seems very slow after that but it's
happening as long as you continue on
with your practice okay so once again
don't rush just trust that you're
improving you can maybe dedicate more
time to your English learning that would
be great and challenge yourself more use
content that's harder for you
for sure do those things but don't
expect uh to see progress really really
fast okay do those things challenge
yourself dedicate more time if you have
it uh but uh just be patient with this
process okay so that's it for today I
hope that you enjoyed this episode and I
hope that you're ready for this new year
and you have uh a good mindset to start
this year and remember that if you want
my help understanding native speakers
when they speak fast if you want my
training then make sure to sign up for
my membership so you can get my
listening practice seminars and if you
become a family member you'll also get
my Advanced podcast episodes where I
speak fast and if you want to challenge
yourself and start to listen to real
conversations between native speakers in
English then join my us conversations
podcast and you'll also get the
transcript for each conversation with
the definitions of key words and phrases
that we use so the link is down below
that's
patreon.com USC conversations and if you
like this podcast please share it with
your friends and family members and give
it a festar r dating and write a review
all right thank you for listening to
this episode and I'll talk to you on the
next episode of listening
[Music]
time